# Sreeharsha Udayashankar

Graduate Research Assistant

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sreeharshau/

**Phone:** +1(647)-248-2965

szudayas@uwaterloo.ca sreeharsha6196@gmail.com

### Education

PhD - Computer Science

University of Waterloo 2021 – Present

MMath (Thesis) - Computer Science

University of Waterloo

2019 – 2021 GPA: 94.5%

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science

PES University, Bangalore, India

2013 - 2017

## **Publications and Awards**

- Falcon Low Latency Network
   Accelerated Scheduling
   I. Kettaneh, S. Udayashankar ,A. Abdel-Hadi and S. Al-Kiswany The 3<sup>rd</sup> P4
   Workshop in Europe (EuroP4 2020)
- Gaming Modeling and Projections The Impact of CPU Performance
   S. Udayashankar, S. Chandra and D. Cherepacha - AMD Asia Tech Conf, 2019
- > International Master's Award of Excellence: University of Waterloo, 2019
- > Spotlight Award: AMD, 2017

### Skills

- Programming: Python, C, C++ and Java
- Parallel Programming: PThreads and OpenMP
- Data Analysis: Numpy, Pandas and scikitlearn
- Web Design: Bootstrap, D3 and JS

# Volunteer Experience

#### Regional Head

Igniting Young Minds (NGO), 2014 - 2017

Igniting Young Minds is an initiative to help underprivileged children by imparting soft-skill training and raising their awareness about the opportunities available to them.

### **About Me**

I am a graduate student researcher at the Waterloo Advanced Systems Laboratory working under the supervision of Prof. Samer Al-Kiswany. My primary research interests lie in Distributed Systems, Cloud Computing and Operating Systems.

In the past couple of years prior to enrolling in this program, I was a member of the CPU Performance and Workloads team at Advanced Micro Devices (AMD). I have also worked as a student researcher on various projects during my undergraduate studies.

## **Professional Experience**

### Design Engineer II

Advanced Micro Devices (AMD), January 2017 – July 2019

I held various positions at AMD ranging from Co-op Engineer up to Design Engineer II. I was a part of the CPU Performance and Workloads team and engaged in driving CPU architectural design using workload performance as an indicator.

- Performance Profiling and Workload Analysis / Characterization
- Performance Modeling **Published** at the AMD Asia Tech Conference 2019
- CPU Performance Simulations and Instruction Tracing

#### Summer Intern

Philips, June 2016 - July 2016

I worked on projects involving Machine Learning as well as designed a KPI Dashboard for Engineering Team Performance using WCF Services.

Awarded for exemplary performance

## Research Experience

#### Graduate Research Assistant

University of Waterloo, September 2019 – Present

I am working under the supervision of Prof. Samer Al-Kiswany in the area of distributed systems and networking.

Accelerating large scale data systems' performance using in-network processing

#### Undergraduate Research Assistant

PES University, August 2015 – December 2016

I was a part of the Cloud Computing and Big Data (CCBD) Lab working under the supervision of Dr K.V. Subramaniam.

- OpenSim An open source simulator for OpenStack
- Video Indexing of Football matches and sentiment analysis of football commentary
- Classification of objects in surveillance footage using OpenCV and Python